Daniel R. Ladd

275 Hillside Drive Henniker, NH 03242 Cell: 603-361-3358

danladd.inbox@gmail.com

Profile

Unconventional data science and analytics professional with over ten years of practical business experience in insurance, banking, and retail industries. Comprehensive background includes roles in management, sales, customer service, purchasing, marketing, and database administration. Known for inventive problem-solving and adeptness in both independent and collaborative settings. Eager to contribute to a forward-thinking organization that fosters growth through supportive mentorship from established data professionals.

Education

Master of Science, Data Science

2024

New England College, Henniker, NH

• Conducted incident analysis for Pat's Peak Ski Patrol identifying critical points of intervention and presenting insights into patient care and mountain safety

Bachelor of Science, Marketing

2005

Plymouth State University, Plymouth, NH

Certifications

AIB Supervisor: ABA

Small Business Banking: ABA Outdoor Emergency Care: NSP

Professional Rescuer CPR: AAOS / ACEP

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

R: RStudio, RMarkdown, tidyverse (dplyr, ggplot, tidyr, readr, stringr, purr, forcats, lubridate), scales, broom, caret, randomForest, xgboost, glmnet

Python: IDLE, Pandas, Numpy, SciPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, scikit-learn

SQL: MySQL, PostgreSQL

Data Visualization Tools

Power BI, Tableau, Spotfire

Relevant Platforms

Google Analytics, Shopify, Kaggle, GitHub, Dataquest

Miscellaneous

Jupyter Notebooks, Apache Spark, MS Excel, Command Line, Zoom, MS Teams

Work Experience

New England College, Henniker, NH

2020 - Present

College Store Manager

- Launched institutionally owned store and manage all facets of college's retail store business
- Source and extract data from diverse origins and formats, employing techniques to merge, bind, and join into analysis-ready environments
- Conduct exploratory data analysis (EDA) using statistical methods, data mining techniques, and visual representations to make preliminary data inferences
- Perform comprehensive data cleaning, preprocessing, and feature engineering to ensure data quality and relevance.
- Develop and implement predictive models leveraging machine learning algorithms to optimize inventory management and facilitate data-driven purchasing decisions
- Utilize time series analysis to aid with strategic decision-making regarding product performance, revenue trends, and market segmentation
- Deploy regression analysis to enhance product placement and marketing strategies, ultimately improving overall customer satisfaction
- Evaluate and access the impact of promotions, discounts, and marketing campaigns on sales and customer engagement through quantitative analysis and A/B testing
- · Employ correlation and market basket analysis to identify strength of product relationships
- Utilize web analytics to enhance customer web experiences and increase web property performance
- Present data to leadership when necessary and advocate for data driven leadership decisioning

Bar Harbor Bank & Trust, Sunapee, NH

2017-2019

Branch Relationship Manager

- Surface and present financial insights to clients, relationship managers, and bank leaders
- Manage, coach, develop, and empower retail staff
- Analyze, monitor, and prioritize bank relationships
- · Analyze, review, and draw insights from reports to minimize losses and ensure regulatory compliance
- Cultivate bonds with business partners to sell across business lines
- Build strong internal and external relationships throughout the community
- Promote brand throughout community by planning and executing events and activities
- Process transactions, open accounts, liaison loans, and review terms, conditions, and policies with customers

NBT Bank, Manchester, NH

2012-2017

Assistant Branch Manager

- Manage operations and assist in the daily leadership of a retail operation
- Consult with clients and prospects to help them make educated decisions about products and services
- Plan, participate and execute marketing and business development activities
- · Handle cash with extreme attention to detail, and adhere to strict policy and procedure
- Schedule, train, and coach staff across four retail branches
- Resolve customer discrepancies and make tactful recommendations

Affiliated Computer Services / Xerox, Manchester, NH

2009-2012

Sr. Production Associate

- Maintain relevant, accurate, valid and reliable data insurance document records
- Forecast delivery volume and schedule deliveries accordingly
- Instituted data capture tools enabling statistical analysis of shipping and receiving volumes
- Answer customer inquiries about product types, shipping data, and departmental capabilities

, dilici